# AKSHAY SINGH

## A Frontend Developer

## CONTACT

- 7607607977
- Jankipuram Extension, Lucknow,UP,226021

## **EDUCATION**

#### **B.Tech**

2015-2019 Electrical Engineering

BABU BANARASI DAS NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY AND MANAGEMENT, Lucknow

## **INTERMEDIATE**

ST.ANTONY INTER COLLEGE,LUCKNOW

2015

## **High School**

Lucknow Public College,Lucknow 2013

## **ABOUT ME**

I am skilled and versatile developer capable of handling all aspects of web application development. I have worked on, highlighting my proficiency in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and front-end frameworks such as React. I am excited to put my skills to use in a professional setting. I am a quick learner and a team player and I am confident that I can be a valuable asset to any web development team.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Newton School**

TRAINEE-FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT

Oct 2022- Present

- Full stack web development along with problem solving.
- Technical stack Learnt : Java ,HTML ,CSS ,JavaScript ,Bootstrap,React.
- Data Structure, Learn different Algorithms
- Participated in Various coding contest organized by the platform.

#### TeamLease Services Limited

## Instrumentation Laboratory India Pvt.

SERVICE ENGINEER

June 2020- May 2023

- Performed onsite installation, modification and maintenance of systems and equipment.
- Worked cross-functionally within organization and external partners, integrators and vendors.
- Provided primary customer support to internal and external customers in a fast-paced environment.
- Completed daily, weekly and monthly checklists on building equipment to maintain records of scheduled maintenance procedures.

## SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Bootstrap
- Java
- React
- Redux

## CERTIFICATIONS

- Completion of course Robotic Process Automation Provided by Great Learning
- Course Completed of Developing Your Professional Image Provide By Linkedin Learning

## **Personal Deatails**

- Father Name Mr.Dharam Singh
- DOB 29-April-1998
- Married Status-Unmarried

## INTERESTS

- Travelling
- Cooking
- Watching Movies

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

### **Amazon Music Clone**

- Features: Amazon Music, a music streaming platform, allowing users to browse, listen to, and discover their favorite songs and artists.
- Tech Stack used: JavaScript, React, CSS, Fetch API.
- Description: Amazon music is a popular music streaming platform that offers a vast library of songs, Albums, and personalized recommendations. The Amazon Music clone will offer users a similar experience, enabling them to enjoy their favorite music and discover new tracks and artists.

### -The Soul Stored

- Features :The Soul Store" is a prominent fashion brand known for its exclusive collection of clothing and accessories for men, women
- Tech Stack used: React, Redux, JS, CSS and Fetch API.
- Description: It is a prominent fashion brand known for its exclusive collection of clothing, The Soul Store" envisions expanding its business online with a comprehensive e-commerce platform.

#### -Movie Deck

- Features :Users can see which is the popular, trending, top rated, and high rated movies list .
- User can go to the different different routes according to their choice to see like high rated, popular ,etc
- Tech Stack used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Fetch API.
- Description: A Movie Deck provides a great userfriendly interface for searching and exploring popular movies.

## -YourDictionary

- Features: Saves the searched words in history Page.
- History Page has global & specific word deletion feature along with phonetic sounds.
- Fully Responsive with eye catching CSS color.
- Tech Stack Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Fetch API
- Description: A Your Dictionary website, which provides a clean and user-friendly interface, Where you can type a word into the search bar, search delivers quick and accurate results.